# YUNUS YURTTURK

# **PROFILE**

Experienced software engineer with 10 years of experience, having electronics engineering background and a diverse skill set across various technology domains. I played a pivotal role in Turkey's specific kind of missile project, as a software engineer and later as software team leader of the project. Presently, I am contributing my expertise as a dedicated software developer for a well known global virtual production company. Over the course of my career, along with pursuing personal interests, I have acquired broad knowledge of multiple technologies, including embedded systems, desktop applications, web development, and mobile app development.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Virtual Production Company

Remote

#### **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Oct 2022 - Present

- Global team, fully remote
- Virtual studio product
- Unreal Engine (specialized in customizing source code, build system and plugin development)
- License management software (Win32, Services, C++, Server/Client)
- CI/CD pipeline implementation and management, preparing installers (Inno Setup and















#### Game Controller Company (Upwork, Contract, Part Time)

Remote

Mar 2023 - Present

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Upwork contractor
- Game controller enhancement software project for PCs
- Signal processing for elimination of drift problems in game controllers
- QT Framework, QML
- C++, SDL2 Library
- 3rd party licensing API integration (WooCommerce Subscriptions)
- Time series analysis & signal processing
- UI Design & Implementation (Figma, QML)
- Still serving as software developer & consultant for the project











Consultant C++ QT QML SDL2 Time Series Signal Processing

#### **TUBITAK SAGE**

Ankara, Turkey Sep 2018 - Oct 2022

#### SOFTWARE TEAM LEADER

TUBITAK (The Scientific and Technological Research Council of Turkey )

- Team leader of ~8 software developers
- Responsible for architecting, developing, and maintaining software projects related to missile development.
- Algorithms integration and tests
- Missile-Aircraft platform integration
- Dual target software development (utilizing same code base for two different target platforms)

Defence Industry Missile Development Team Lead Avionics Complex System





+90 505 709 8376

yunusyurtturk@gmail.com

yunusyurtturk.com Ankara, Turkey

## SKILLS =====

#### Programming:

C++, C, QT, QML, C#, Scripting, Powershell, Unreal Engine

#### **Software Development:**

Object Oriented Programming, Design Patterns, CI/CD, Software Architecture, JIRA, UML

Mathematics, Signal Processing, Time Series Analysis, Electronics

#### **Embedded Software:**

Xilinx Zyng, ARM Architecture, Bare Metal, RTOS

#### **Developer Tools:**

Git, Github Actions, CMake

Figma, .Net, Flutter, Linux, Web Development

#### LANGUAGES =

Turkish Native English C1

#### INTERESTS =

Computer Popular Science Games Kickbox Animes

## Ankara, Turkey

Sep 2013 - Oct 2022

#### SR. SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Defence industry
- Realtime mission computer software development
- Deep knowledge about ARM Architecture, specifically Cortex-A processors
- Bare metal embedded software development
- Expert in Micrium III OS/Kernel (RTOS).
- Extensive TCP/IP experience, integrated and customized the stack from the lowest 'physical' layer to the highest 'application' layer.
- Desktop software development, using C++, C#, CLR C++, QT, Borland C++
- Hardware and software simulation of avionic devices
- JIRA Administration























# **Personal Projects**

Ankara, Turkey

#### MOTION CONTROLLED GAME CONTROLLER

Oct 2020 - Jun 2021

- Similar to Nintendo Wii, developing a game controller project based on physical movements
- Arduino & BN0055 9 Degree of freedom IMU Sensor for sampling movement data
- Advanced time series analysis & processing
- Reverse engineering & DLL hooking
- Implemented complex GUI software to support monitoring, training and testing the project
- https://github.com/yunusyurtturk/BNO055SensorPad





Signal Processing Time Series IMU Game Controller Reverse Engineering Dynamic Time Warping

#### **FLUTTER CARD GAME**

Oct 2021 - Jun 2022

- Pisti game (a common deck game played with 52 cards)
- Flutter based
- Single player, multi player, realtime
- Integrated Firebase (Google Cloud) as backend, authentication and database services
- Multiplayer game without one line of server code









#### **ILAN HARITASI (BAZAARERS)**

2011 - 2016

- Bazaar refers to a market in a Middle Eastern country. \*
- Location based & social buy/sell network
- Large-scale project that took significant time and effort.
- Google maps integration
- HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap for frontend
- PHP (Laravel) and MySQL for backend
- LAMP server setup, using Digital Ocean droplets
- Native android application development
- Personally executed every aspect of the implementation.
- https://github.com/yunusyurtturk/BazaarersArchive

















# **EDUCATION**

**BSc in Electrical and Electronics Engineering** 

**Hacettepe University** 

Sep 2008 - Nov 2013